Jason Lee

2416 NW 176th Street, Edmond, OK 73012. (405) 343-1964. jason@steeplesoft.com. http://blogs.steeplesoft.com

Principal Java Developer

Solutions-oriented enterprise developer with over 16 years of broad-based, enterprise development. Proven ability to handle all stages of the SDLC, from requirements gathering and systems and database design, to implementation, deployment and support. Always eager to push technologies to their limits and learn new ones in order to meet the customers' needs.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Javascript, Python, PHP, Delphi, C/C++, HTML

Tools: JSF, JAX-RS, CDI, EJB, JPA, Spring, AngularJS, YUI, Dojo, Junit, TestNG, Selenium, Git, SVN

Mobile: Android

Professional Experience

Sun Microsystems/Oracle Corporation – Principal Member of Technical Staff, July 2008 – Present Designed and implemented both GUI and RESTful administration interfaces for the GlassFish and Weblogic application servers.

- Improved user experience by modernizing the GlassFish Administration Console, integrating legacy JSF-based framework with current (ajax-enabled) standards, reducing page load times from several several seconds to an average of 0.5 seconds.
- Provided stable, consistent REST interface for internal and external customers
- Implemented plugin architecture for the REST interface, allowing internal and external customers to provide their own plugins based on individual needs
- Increased product reliability by designing and developing a testing framework to prevent feature loss and bug regression

Cub Tracker – Creator, April 2011 – Present

Designed and implement a mobile (Android) application to assist parents and leaders in tracking the progress of Cub Scouts

• Over 10,000 downloads with a current install base of almost 4,000 users

Objectstream – Software Architect, May 2007 – May 2008

Worked with team of business analysts and Subject Matter Experts to design a training tracking system for the Federal Aviation Administration's Air Traffic Organization.

- Drafted architecture documents detailing the technical details for implementing the desired solution
- Provided proof-of-concept implementation to test the architecture in the ATO's data center environment

International Environmental Corporation – Senior Software Engineer, January 2005 – May 2007 Designed, implemented, and supported systems to support in-house customers

- Increased reliability, availability and stability of backend database by migrating from MySQL 4 to PostgreSOL 8
- Increased application reliability by implementing unit and functional testing framework
- Made systems more predictable and easier to maintain by standardizing on a few, core technologies
- Mentored and trained teammates on new or unfamiliar technologies

Jason Lee – Page 2

Hobby Lobby Stores – Programmer/Analyst, July 2001 – December 2004

Supported store back office systems to allow for sales/time reporting, etc, as well as integrating point of sales systems with iSeries backend

- Decreased downtime for stores' back office system by replacing aging AIX server with fault-tolerant Linux-based systems
- Improved end-user experience with back office system by delivering frequent bug and stability fixes to 300+ remote stores
- Insured sales were smooth and efficient by monitoring and maintaining the credit and gift card networks

Red River Solutions – Programmer/Analyst, July 1998 – July 2001

Designed, implemented, and supported systems to facilitate the medical records retrieval process for our call centers

- Help design and implement distributed workflow engine that powered the business
- Led a small team of front-end developers, writing both Java- and C++-based applications
- Mentored and managed junior developers
- Simplified and sped up end-user application development process by designing an application framework that rested on top of the C++Builder GUI code
- Improved product quality by installing and maintaining a bug tracking system
- Maintained local area network for the Tulsa-based development office

Wal-Mart Stores – Programmer/Analyst, June 1997 – June 1998

Developed systems to aid the logistics management teams

- Helped design and develop an extension to the decision support system for the Logistics department
- Saved the company over \$168 million dollars by implementing a system to locate and identify inventory that had been sitting in the distribution centers for too long

Publications

Tips for Writing Pluggable Java EE Applications – Java Tech Journal

http://jaxenter.com/java-tech-journal/JTJ-2012-06

JSFTemplating and Woodstock: Component Authoring Made Easy – Sun Developer Network

http://java.sun.com/developer/technicalArticles/J2EE/jsf_templating/index.html

IEC donates custom JSF component to Mojarra Scales – Sun Microsystems

http://www.jsfcentral.com/articles/trenches_7.html

Jason Lee: Postmortem for JavaOne 2008 – The Server Side

http://www.theserverside.com/news/thread.tss?thread_id=49343

IEC: A Cooling Company Which Prefers Hot Software – Sun Microsystems

https://blogs.oracle.com/stories/entry/international environmental

Jason Lee in depth: Mojarra and Scales – JSFCentral

http://www.jsfcentral.com/articles/lee-03-09.html

Education and Certifications

B.S. Computer Science

Oklahoma Baptist University, Shawnee, OK

August 1993 - May 1997

Sun Certified Java Developer (SCJP 5.0)

September 2006